Nguyen Thi Chi Lam

DATA VERIFICATION SPECIALIST



Date of birth 15/10/2001

Gender Female

Address
District 5, Ho Chi Minh City

Phone 0967423249

Email

nguyenlam151001@gmail.com

Website linkedin.com/in/lâm-nguyễn-a42b31286

Objective

Develop a career in data management and verification as a Data Verification Specialist, ensuring the accuracy, consistency and integrity of information in the system. At the same time, contribute to optimizing the testing process, improving data quality and supporting efficient operations.

Skills

- Data Analysis and Visualization: PowerBl, Excel
- Programming: Python, SQL
- Project Management: Jira, Trello
- Stakeholder Engagement & Communication
- Soft Skills: Analytical Thinking, Problem-Solving, Communication and Collaboration

Activities

June 2020 - Sep 2020

Manga Trans & Edit Team

Volunteer Translator

May 2020 - Jun 2020

UIT SAFE Volunteer

Participate in the volunteer movement to measure the temperature of students, lecturers and visitors to UIT during the Covid19 outbreak.

Dec 2019

UIT ENGLISH SPEAKING CONTEST

Participate in the English contest about the era of technological development.

Certifications

TOEIC Certificate (Score 835) | 2024

Experience

Dec 2024 - Present

FREELANCE RESEARCH ANALYST

- Collect and research scientific articles related to Quality of Accounting Information Systems (QAIS).
- Analyze survey data using SPSS, perform Exploratory Factor Analysis (EFA) and calculate Cronbach's Alpha to test the reliability of the data.
- Support research for thesis on QAIS in enterprise.

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

CJ OLIVENETWORKS VINA

BUSINESS ANALYST & QA TESTER INTERN

Business Analyst:

- Analyzed As-is business processes and suggested improvements.
- Designed a user-friendly contract management screen.
- Defined business requirements and documented workflows using Jira/Confluence.

QA Tester:

- Developed test cases and conducted functional testing.
- Reported and tracked software defects in Jira, collaborating with developers to improve product quality.

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

CAT MARKET RESEARCH & ADVISOR

- Researched and observed market trends, breed popularity, and buyer preferences.
- Evaluate regional prices and demand based on experience and observations.
- Advise customers on appropriate breed selection and basic care.
- Negotiate reasonable prices between buyers and sellers.

Education

Oct 2019 - Nov 2024

UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - UIT

Major: Information System

 Graduation Project: Forecasting gold price based on machine learning.